[Automatic Transcript Recognizability 66%]
But, instr _bill nine-ninety threes well _ Could Mr. Chair. SB 993 as well?
[Automatic Transcript Recognizability 55%]
_daily on boy it's okay _sheena For Senator De Leon? Go ahead. Okay.
[Automatic Transcript Recognizability 86%]
_on still is a still that was not create a mandate Senator De Leon's bill is a bill that would create a mandate
[Automatic Transcript Recognizability 90%]
but it would allow schools to have a programs a study of course but it would allow schools to have a program of study, a course
[Automatic Transcript Recognizability 97%]
a study on the for several program some of you may be aware of study, on the Bracero Program. Some of you may be aware
[Automatic Transcript Recognizability 75%]
_a california in particular right about the time of world war _ in California in particular, right about the time of World War II,
[Automatic Transcript Recognizability 85%]
_several program was hannibal part of how we did agriculture the Bracero Program was an integral part of how we did agriculture.
[Automatic Transcript Recognizability 92%]
as people moved into a part of the war effort there was some concerns as to whether or not As people moved into a part of the war effort there was some concerns as to whether or not
[Automatic Transcript Recognizability 96%]
california would be able to continue to supply food and other material that we California would be able to continue to supply food and other material that we
[Automatic Transcript Recognizability 92%]
were providing at the time divisional program was instrumental in that number people were providing at the time. The Bracero Program was instrumental in that number of people
[Automatic Transcript Recognizability 86%]
are unaware of what took place this would be a are unaware of what took place. This would be a
[Automatic Transcript Recognizability 77%]
_study _mandate and not curriculum of study, not a mandate and not
[Automatic Transcript Recognizability 82%]
_but that schools to look at having a curriculum a study on a requirement, but that schools to look at having a curriculum a study on
[Automatic Transcript Recognizability 79%]
_several program there's no appropriation because _he obviously the Bracero Program. There's no appropriation because it would be obviously
[Automatic Transcript Recognizability 88%]
at the discretion of that school district without a specific appropriation _ at the discretion of that school district without a specific appropriation, nor would there be a mandate if there were to occur.
[Automatic Transcript Recognizability 71%]
_at _great anyway favor speaking out for the bills Great. Anyone in favor of speaking for the bill sir?
[Automatic Transcript Recognizability 81%]
or I am not sure because I got this I am not sure because I got this packet around two hours ago.
[Automatic Transcript Recognizability 77%]
_slowness accompany opposition please come forward Anyone in opposition please come forward.
[Automatic Transcript Recognizability 76%]
_on questions comments from the community. Seeing none, questions, comments from the committee?
[Automatic Transcript Recognizability 67%]
Moved in _go ahead with your Moved in second go ahead with your close.
[Automatic Transcript Recognizability 66%]
_I would _and I think and again I think Again, I would an 'I' vote. I think, and again I think,
[Automatic Transcript Recognizability 97%]
_become important just as we look at contributions of different groups this becomes important just as we look at contributions of different groups.
[Automatic Transcript Recognizability 78%]
california and disrespected unique California in this respect is unique
[Automatic Transcript Recognizability 81%]
because agriculture was such an integral part of what made _ because agriculture was such an integral part of what made this
[Automatic Transcript Recognizability 74%]
_and tercel program was instrumental part of that particularly as a part of the state grow and Bracero Program was instrumental part of that particularly as a part of the
[Automatic Transcript Recognizability 87%]
_leopard were often the connection isn't made between World War II effort were often the connection isn't made between
[Automatic Transcript Recognizability 75%]
the several program and world war two _ the Bracerp Program and World War II and
[Automatic Transcript Recognizability 70%]
_part that played in the _I would _when I _you I've seen a lot of these the instrumental part that played in the growth. I would ask for an 'I' Mr. Chair. I've seen a lot of these
[Automatic Transcript Recognizability 92%]
bills as have committee members from commemorating ronald reagan bills as have committee members from commemorating Ronald Reagan
[Automatic Transcript Recognizability 88%]
to labor history I never support them because. to labor history. I never support them because.
[Automatic Transcript Recognizability 72%]
It seems like _doing _know _use or _sort of It seems like we're already doing it and don't need these. Or we're sort of
[Automatic Transcript Recognizability 86%]
micro managing curriculum I have talked history _history for a large and micro-managing curriculum, I have taught history, US History, for a large and,
[Automatic Transcript Recognizability 92%]
_twenty years in high school I did teach about the around twenty years in high school. I did teach about the
[Automatic Transcript Recognizability 72%]
_world war two I never realized Braceros and World War II. I never realized
[Automatic Transcript Recognizability 93%]
_the state legislation that didn't allow me to do it because I thought I was already a lot that the state legislation that didn't allow me to do it because I thought I was already allowed
[Automatic Transcript Recognizability 90%]
too and that's why I I'm not sure what this really does doesn't what people are already allowed to do to do it, and that's why I'm not sure what this really does other than what people are already allowed to do.
[Automatic Transcript Recognizability 70%]
_was just. Which is probably why I'll lay off of it.
[Automatic Transcript Recognizability 92%]
It only sets forth the ideas that you want to say that the legislature It only sets forth the ideas that you want to say that the legislature
[Automatic Transcript Recognizability 87%]
with like _be emphasis on the with like there to be emphasis on the
[Automatic Transcript Recognizability 97%]
_program that's why it's not a mandate it's not a specific curriculum there's Bracero Program. That's why it's not a mandate, it's not a specific curriculum, there's
[Automatic Transcript Recognizability 99%]
no money in it but it's just to say this is something that we would like to be done so no money in it. But it's just to say this is something that we would like to be done so
that people understood that people understood
[Automatic Transcript Recognizability 84%]
the contributions of the visceral program and the workers were involved in it so you're, the contributions of the Bracero Program and the workers were involved in it. So you're,
[Automatic Transcript Recognizability 97%]
you're, you're absolutely right schools can do this now should they you're, you're absolutely right. Schools can do this now, should they
[Automatic Transcript Recognizability 75%]
_and we would hope that more history teachers would be a _you choose to, and we would hope that more history teachers would be enlightened as you,
[Automatic Transcript Recognizability 87%]
_recognizing devaluing so much time you pick and choose what Mr. Chair, recognizing the value. (Norby speaking) There's only so much time. You pick and choose what
[Automatic Transcript Recognizability 84%]
would you teach you a and hopefully textbook goes along other comments or questions from you teach and hopefully textbook goes along. Other comments or questions from,
[Automatic Transcript Recognizability 81%]
_from the committee if not we'll. from the committee. If not we'll hear the roll.
[Automatic Transcript Recognizability 67%]
Brownie _be. Brownley? Norbey?
[Automatic Transcript Recognizability 72%]
Darby not _I know I mean I don't I you Norby not voting. Ammiano? I. Buchanan?
[Automatic Transcript Recognizability 75%]
_you can and I butler's carter harder _ Buchanan I. Butler? Carter? Carter I. Eng?
[Automatic Transcript Recognizability 82%]
And, I growth. Eng I. Growth?
[Automatic Transcript Recognizability 96%]
_not voting haldeman, Growth not voting. Halderman?
[Automatic Transcript Recognizability 74%]
haldeman no wagner, wagner no williams, williams _ Haldeman no. Wagner? Wagner no. Williams? Williams I.
[Automatic Transcript Recognizability 80%]
So, it has five-cent kj _villas on-call thank you very much Five votes the bill is on-call. Thank you very much.
[Automatic Transcript Recognizability 93%]
your presentation _steinberg I believe you're ready. Senator Steinberg, I believe you're ready.